dyndns.com 2018-12-31

# Oracle's Privacy Policy

_Dyn has been[acquired](https://www.oracle.com/corporate/acquisitions/dyn/index.html) by Oracle and will soon transition to the Oracle Privacy Policy. Click here to view the Oracle Privacy Policy. Please note that the provisions of Oracle’s Privacy Policy for Dyn Services below will remain active until the policy transition is complete_

Last Modified: February 15, 2018

**ORACLE’S PRIVACY POLICY FOR DYN SERVICES (“Privacy Policy”)**

Oracle America, Inc. (“Oracle,” “Us,” or “We”) recognizes that privacy is important, and we want to be clear with you about our privacy practices. This Privacy Policy describes how Oracle collects, uses and shares information collected from you through your use of Oracle’s websites for Dyn Services (like www.dyn.com and other websites that reference this Privacy Policy, collectively referred to as the “Sites”) and the services offered through the Sites (the “Services”). If you are curious about Oracle’s privacy practices for Oracle’s Internet Performance Tools (like Oracle’s RUM Beacons and Recursive DNS services), please visit: [http://dyn.com/legal/ipm-tools-privacy-policy/](http://dyn.com/legal/ipm-tools-privacy-policy/).

**HOW ORACLE COLLECTS INFORMATION AND THE TYPES OF INFORMATION COLLECTED**

Any time you use Oracle’s Sites or Services, information is generated. Some of this information is considered “Personal Information,” meaning information that either directly identifies you individually (like your name, address, email, or billing information) or could reasonably be used to identify you in combination with other data. Other information is considered “Anonymous Information,” meaning information that does not directly identify, and cannot reasonably be linked with other data to identify you individually.

Oracle collects information from you in the following ways:

A. YOU GIVE IT TO US

When you visit or use our Sites or use our Services, you may provide us with information. For example, when downloading an Oracle whitepaper or setting up a new DynID account, we will prompt you to provide us with your name, physical address, email address and phone number.

B. WE RECEIVE IT FROM THIRD PARTIES

Oracle engages with third party vendors to try to determine new customers who might be interested in Oracle’s Dyn Services. In such instances third parties may give Oracle your name and contact information.

C.  WE AUTOMATICALLY COLLECT IT FROM YOU

While visiting our Sites or using our Services, we may automatically collect information from you through the use of cookies, web server logs, and other mechanisms.  For example, when you visit a Site, we automatically collect device identifiers (e.g., device model, operating system, browser version, and other data that may be used to identify a device), IP addresses, device configurations, browser history, information about Site usage, and geographic location data.

NOTE ON CROSS BORDER TRANSFERS: Oracle has established a global network presence and may process information on our servers in many countries around the world, including the United States. You agree that we may process information on a server located outside the country where you reside.

NOTE ON CHILDREN’S PERSONAL INFORMATION: Oracle does not knowingly collect any personal information (as defined under the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act) from children under the age of 13. If we learn that we have collected or received personal from a child under 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information. If you believe that we might have such information, please contact us at the contact information provided below.

NOTE ON COOKIES AND SIMILAR TECHNOLOGY

Oracle uses cookies and web beacons to automatically collect information in connection with your use of the Sites and Services.

“Cookies” are small files that are placed on an individual’s computer when you interact with the Sites or Services.  Cookies are often used to enable you to more easily communicate and interact with the Sites and Services. “Web beacons” (also known as “single-pixel” or “clear” GIFs) include electronic images embedded in the Site or in communications sent through the Services which are invisible to users. Web beacons collect information, such as identifiers, time and date of access, and descriptions of the pages or communications in which the web beacons are embedded.

We may use cookies or web beacons on the Sites or in communications sent through the Services for various purposes, including for example:

  * Saving user preferences;
  * Customizing content of the Site for individual users;
  * Ensuring that users are not repeatedly sent the same banner ads;
  * Recording session information;
  * Fraud prevention;
  * Saving certain information about users of the Sites and others who visit the Sites;
  * Keeping track of whether you’ve had a chance to open an email or view an advertisement; and
  * Otherwise facilitating and enhancing interaction with the Sites.

Oracle may contract with third party service providers who also may also use cookies or web beacons in connection with the Sites or communications regarding the Services. For example, Oracle uses Google Analytics to get aggregated information on our Site’s performance (you can learn more about how Google uses data when you use our Sites by visiting www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/). Similarly, we may use an outside advertisement serving company to display advertisements on the Site or in communications sent through the Services. The advertisement serving company may place and collect cookies or web beacons when it displays an advertisement on the Site or through the Services. The information these third parties collect may be associated with other information about you, or they may collect information about your online activities over time and across different websites and other online services. We do not control these third parties’ tracking technologies or how they may be used.

**HOW ORACLE USES AND SHARES INFORMATION**

Oracle uses your information for a variety of purposes related to provisioning, maintaining and improving the Sites and Services, as well as for developing new services. For example, Oracle uses your information to administer your account, provide technical support and to communicate with you about your account. Oracle also uses your information to send you new and exciting information about Oracle.  
Other than as described above, Oracle does not use your Personal Information, nor does it share your personal information with companies, organizations or individuals outside of Oracle, unless one of the following circumstances apply:

  * Oracle has your express consent;
  * It is for Oracle’s internal use, research and product development;
  * It is for domain registration in accordance with the RAA and ICANN policies. (Please see Domain Registration section below for more information regarding our treatment of Personal Information in connection with our domain name registration services.)
  * It is for external processing by our affiliates or other trusted third parties we use to support our business based on our instructions or other appropriate confidentiality and security measures (for example, companies that help Oracle improve its web site’s usability or understand customer interests); or
  * It is to detect, prevent or otherwise address fraud, security or other legal related issues.

Note that Oracle may share Anonymous Information with third parties. Oracle may also share Personal Information with companies, organizations or individuals outside of Oracle if we have a good-faith belief that access, use, preservation, or disclosure of the information is reasonably necessary to:

  * meet any applicable law, regulation, legal process or enforceable governmental request;
  * enforce applicable agreements or adherence to terms and conditions, including investigation of potential violations; and
  * protect against harm to the rights, property or safety of Oracle, our users, third parties or the public as required or permitted by law.

If Oracle is involved in a merger, acquisition or asset sale, we will continue to ensure the confidentiality of any Personal Information and give affected users notice before Personal Information is transferred or becomes subject to a different privacy policy.

Oracle does not sell or license your Personal Information to a third party for that third party’s own direct marketing purposes.

**YOUR PRIVACY CHOICES**

TRACKING TECHNOLOGIES. Most browsers will allow you to erase cookies from your computer hard drive, block acceptance of cookies, or receive a warning before a cookie is stored. You may also be able to refuse certain web beacons by adjusting the settings on your browser or email software. Please refer to your browser or email software instructions or help screen to learn more about these functions.  Note that if you disable or refuse cookies, some parts of the Sites may be inaccessible or not function properly.

ACCESSING AND CORRECTING YOUR INFORMATION.Should you wish to access, amend, correct, or delete any Personal Information about you, please contact privacy_ww@oracle.com. Oracle will use commercially reasonable efforts to respond to such requests within thirty days, except where the burden or expense of providing access or requested changes would be disproportionate to the risks to your privacy in the case in question. Please note that your ability to use, and Oracle’s ability to provide, the Services may depend upon the use of your Personal Information. As such, you agree that Oracle will not be liable for any inability to provide all or a portion of the Services that may result from Oracle’s compliance with any request to amend, correct or delete any of your Personal Information.

UNSUBSCRIBING FROM COMMUNICATIONS. **** If you no longer wish to receive Newsletters, Support Related Emails or other promotional communications, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each newsletter, by going to [https://account.dyn.com/profile/mailinglist.html](https://account.dyn.com/profile/mailinglist.html) or emailing privacy_ww@oracle.com. In order to ensure the integrity, security and operation of our systems and networks, we do not allow you to unsubscribe from Service Notices.

**APPLICABILITY**

This Privacy Policy applies to Sites and Services that make specific reference to or contain a link to this Policy. It does not apply to Oracle sites, services and products that do not display or link to this statement or that have their own privacy statements. If you are interested in Oracle’s privacy practices in connection with some of its specific internet monitoring tools please see [http://dyn.com/legal/ipm-tools-privacy-policy/](http://dyn.com/legal/ipm-tools-privacy-policy/).

**EU US PRIVACY SHIELD**

DYN has been acquired by Oracle. Oracle is a global corporation with operations in over 80 countries and has developed global data security practices designed to ensure that your personal information is appropriately protected. Please note that personal information may be transferred, accessed and stored globally as necessary in accordance with this Statement. 

Oracle complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention when a customer and Oracle have agreed by contract that transfers of personal information from the European Economic Area (“EEA”) or Switzerland will be transferred and processed pursuant to the Privacy Shield for the relevant services. When conducting those activities on behalf of its EEA or Swiss customers, Oracle holds and/or processes personal information provided by the EEA or Swiss customer at the direction of the customer. Oracle will then be responsible for ensuring that third parties acting as an agent on our behalf do the same. 

Oracle has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles. If there is any conflict between the terms in this Statement and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit https://www.privacyshield.gov/list. 

The following entities are covered entities under Oracle’s Privacy Shield self-certification: Delphi Asset Management Corporation; MICROS Fidelio Worldwide LLC; Oracle America, Inc.; Oracle Financial Services Software America, Inc.; Oracle Financial Services Software, Inc.; Oracle International Corporation; Oracle Taiwan LLC; Bronto Software, LLC; Monexa, LLC, NetSuite, Inc.; OrderMotion, Inc.; Dynamic Network Services, Inc. With respect to personal information received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Framework, Oracle is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission and commits to cooperate with EU data protection authorities. 

Dispute Resolution

If you have any complaints regarding our compliance with this Statement, you should first contact us. We will investigate and attempt to resolve complaints and disputes regarding use and disclosure of personal information in accordance with this Statement. 

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request. Under certain conditions, more fully described on the Privacy Shield website, you may invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted. 

**DOMAIN REGISTRATION**

In order to provide domain registration services, Oracle is required to be an ICANN accredited registrar. As an ICANN accredited registrar, Oracle is required to share, process and maintain Personal Information of customers of its domain registration services in accordance with the ICANN Registrar Accreditation Agreement (as amended from time to time) (“RAA”) and policies related to the domain name registration services provided by Oracle. By using Oracle’s domain name registration services, you agree that Oracle may use, share, transfer, process and retain any Personal Information provided to Oracle in connection with such services in accordance with the version RAA by which Oracle is bound and any applicable ICANN policies. For more information regarding the RAA and ICANN policies, you contact Oracle or [www.icann.org](http://www.icann.org/). Please note that Oracle is currently bound by the terms and conditions of the 2013 RAA.

**SECURITY**

Oracle has implemented policies that include administrative, technical, and physical safeguards designed to help protect Personal Information against unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. While Oracle strives to protect your privacy, due to many reasons, including the inherent security flaws in the internet, Oracle cannot guarantee the security of any information you disclose to us and, as such, you agree that your disclosure of such information is at your own risk.

**INFORMATION PROCESSED BY ORACLE’S CLIENTS**

Our clients may provide us with Personal Information belonging to their customers or other third parties in connection with their use of our services. Oracle does not control the content or nature of the information processed by our clients in connection with their use of our services. An individual who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate Personal Information processed by one of our clients should direct his/her request to the client (the data controller) directly.

**PUBLIC FORUMS**

Oracle may make chat rooms, forums, message boards, and/or news groups available to its users. Please note that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information.

**CHANGES TO PRIVACY POLICY**

We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy from time to time. We will post any changes to this Privacy Policy on this page and, if the changes are significant, we will provide a more prominent notice, which may include sending notice to you by email or posting notice of such changes on Oracle’s public status page for Dyn Services (www.dynstatus.com) or Oracle’s home page for Dyn Services (www.dyn.com).

**CONTACT INFORMATION**

If you have any questions regarding this Privacy Policy, Oracle may be contacted at:

By email:  
privacy_ww@oracle.com

By mail:  
Oracle America, Inc.  
500 Oracle Parkway  
Redwood Shores, CA 94065  
Attn: General Counsel, Legal Department
